Hey everyone
大家好
I just launched my Patreon page
我們的頻道有自己的Patreon了
More info at the end.
詳細信息在視頻結尾處
You are… looking at my personal work.
畫面上的……是我的個人作品
I have been creating these small videos since my days in university.
從大學開始，我保持著創作這些小視頻的習慣
I find the creative process to be calming.
創作的過程讓我安定
One of the few times, when I can be one with myself.
那是我唯一能感到安寧的時刻
And that, to me…
對我而言
Is a necessity.
創作是生活必需品
I started Accented Cinema, as a creative project.
最初，《異聲影院》也隻是一個小創作
I enjoy the process.
我喜歡創作的過程
And I can to talk about things my friends don’t understand.
特別是當我談論一些無人討論的事物時
I grew up in the province of Guangdong in China.
我在中國廣東長大
Movies from all around Asia collide in this trading hub.
在這個貿易中心裡，亞洲各地的影視作品四方而來
I could turn on the TV, and see Stephen Chow on one channel,
打開電視就能看到周星馳
Dragon Ball Z on the next,
或是《龍珠》
and Ang Lee on another.
或是李安
All of that, defined my childhood.
這一切塑造了我的童年印象
It was only later in life that I realized,
一直到我長大了
This was somewhat of an unique experience.
我才發現，我的童年印象並不普遍
No one else I talk to understands what I’m talking about.
身邊沒有人和我有共同語言
You know that Street Fighter movie?
你看過《街頭霸王》電影嗎？
No, the one made in Hong Kong...
不，我說的是香港的……
At age 14.
14歲的時候
I moved to Montreal with my parent.
我跟隨家人搬到了蒙特利爾
It took a toll on me.
忽然的變換讓我無所適從
The world suddenly got a lot bigger.
世界忽然變大了
And I got a lot lonelier.
我忽然變孤單了
I couldn’t speak a word of French.
我一句法語都不會講
So, movies became my main way of fooling my brain into thinking I’m communicating.
電影便變成了每天自我交流的唯一方式
It kept me busy.
忙碌
It drowned out my sensory inputs.
自我封閉
It dealt with my emotions
自我麻醉
I would stay up late into the night.
有時，我會一天看四部電影
Watching the fourth movie of the day.
一直看到深夜凌晨
Waiting for the world to end.
靜靜等待世界末日
I later went to film school.
后來，我去了電影學院
Because I didn’t know much else.
畢竟我也不懂其他東西了
When others spent their times discovering themselves.
當其他人在發現自己的時候
All my times were devoted on movies,
我的時間都花在了電影上
good or bad.
好片爛片照樣看
In college, I learnt how to speak.
大學裡，我重新學會了語言表達
Both English, and film.
說英語，說電影
I spoke to no one in particular.
我依然沒有談話的對象
And no one was listening.
也沒有人聽我說話
It was mostly essays and scripts.
語言都隻存在於論文和劇本上
But the process of creation, however simple, gave me a voice.
但是簡單的創作過程給了我表達自己的方式
Suddenly, I could speak again.
忽然間，我能說話了
I could forget my accent.
我可以忽略自己的口音
I’m in control of my body…
我能表達自己想要表達的事
I have things to say...
我有話要講
Accented Cinema started out as just another creative project.
《異聲影院》最初隻是一個小小的創作
Something to keep me busy.
一個佔領閑暇時間的策劃
It’s like singing in the shower.
就像是浴室裡唱歌一樣
I just want to talk about my childhood memories.
我不過想花點時間談談我的童年記憶
Questions I wondered about.
關於那些我思考過的問題
Films I grew up with.
關於我看過的電影
I talked.
我說了幾句話
And twenty thousand of you decided to listen.
卻被兩萬多人聽見了
I’m making this video,
我想通過這個視頻
because reality finally struck me.
告訴大家，我終於反應過來了
That I am not alone any more.
我已經不是一個人在說話
My voice has gathered a crowd.
我的聲音帶來了好多人
And they are talking back
而大家都在跟我交談
This is not my channel any more.
我的頻道不再是我的頻道
This is our channel now.
這是我們的頻道了
Thank you, for being here.
感謝你的到來
Hey everyone
大家好
Thanks for watching this random extra video.
希望大家喜歡這個額外視頻
If you follow this channel, you probably know
關注這個頻道的人大概都知道
Two of our videos have been copyright claimed
我們最近有兩個視頻被版權申索
And dispute rejected.
不能賺取廣告得益
Each video in this channel takes about 40 to 60 hours of research, writing and editing.
這個頻道的每個視頻背后都有40到60小時的工時
Without a stable revenue, the channel cannot stay afloat.
沒有穩定的收入，這個頻道無法持續下去
This is why I launched my Patreon page
因此，我為這個頻道建立了Patreon賬號
A place where you can purchase extra perks,
在這個網頁裡，你可以購買一些額外內容
and directly support this channel financially.
並在財政上直接支持這個頻道的運營
You can get extra videos, script previews, vote on video topics
你可以購買額外視頻、優先看劇本、投票決定視頻主題
And also be more involved in the creative process.
並在節目創作過程中提出反響
If you’d like to help, hop on over to my Patreon page and have a look.
若你希望對頻道伸出援手，請到頻道的Patreon頁面看看
If you can’t afford direct donation, that is okay, too.
但不能直接支持也沒有關系
Stick around and keep watching our videos.
繼續看我們的節目，就是莫大的支持
Regardless, you have my sincerest of gratitude.
無論如何，請接受我最衷心的感謝
See you in the next episode.
我們下一期節目見